# Luis Martínez Mendoza

#### Contact

Location: Trujillo, Perú

Email: lemartinezmendoza@gmail.com

Phone: +51 939374139

## **Summary**

Junior Full Stack Developer with one year of development experience. I have participated in several projects using technologies such as JavaScript, Next.js, Node.js, NestJS and MongoDB, collaborating in multidisciplinary teams and agile environments. I have soft skills in teamwork, effective communication and problem solving.

## **Work Experience**

Junior Full Stack Developer, REWORTH

Period: January 2023 - June 2023

Responsabilities:

- Implementation of new functionalities in frontend and backend applications following the specifications and requirements established and using technologies such as Next.js, React-Query, Chakra UI, Node.js, NestJS and MongoDB.
- Technical troubleshooting, testing and debugging code to ensure quality and proper functioning of applications.

Key accomplishments:

- Developed an internal administration panel that facilitated the management and tracking tasks of the company and improved the user experience using Next.js, React-Query and Chakra UI.
- Collaborated in a company service that used Node.js, NestJS, TypeScript and followed Clean Architecture. In addition, I performed the implementation of unit tests.
- Documented some endpoints using Swagger to improve the understanding and use of the API.
- Collaborated in an agile team, using tools such as Jira and GitHub for task management and version control, which allowed for collaborative development and successful on-time delivery.

Coordinator of Student Projects, OpenBootcamp

Period: September 2022 - November 2022

Responsabilities:

- Coordination of tasks, setting project objectives and deadlines in conjunction with other project coordinators.
- Maintain continuous control and follow-up of projects.
- Provide guidance and support to other students regarding work methodologies and technologies used to create the projects.

Key accomplishments:

- Participated in the development of four projects, coordinating tasks, setting goals and providing guidance and support to other students to ensure the success of the projects.
- Participated in the creation and deployment of full stack web applications using technologies such as JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express, Tailwind CSS, MongoDB, Git and GitHub.
- Used GitHub issues for tracking and task management, which allowed us to have a clear and organized record of project progress.

Research intern, Universidad Nacional de Trujillo

Period: October 2021 - February 2022

Responsabilities:

- Search and download relevant atmospheric data from the NOAA data repository.
- Statistical processing and analysis of downloaded atmospheric data using Python.
- Creation of heat maps and graphs of detected anomalies using Python.

## Key accomplishments:

- Implemented the download of atmospheric data from the NOAA repository using the FTP protocol and Python.
- Performed data analysis using Python's numpy, pandas and xarray libraries to better understand the patterns and causes behind the El Niño Costero phenomenon.
- Developed several scripts that allowed the creation of the plots in a simple way and reduced the retrieval time during the anomaly analysis using the xarray, cartopy and matplotlib Python libraries.

#### **Hard Skills**

- Programming languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python
- Frameworks and technologies: React, Next.js, Node.js, Express.js, NestJS
- Databases: MongoDB
- Development tools: Git, GitHub, Postman, Jira
- Agile methodologies: ScrumDocumentation: Swagger

### **Soft Skills**

- Teamwork
- Effective communication
- Problem solving
- Resilience

#### Education

Full Stack Developer, OpenBootcamp Period: January 2022 - October 2022

Bachelor's degree in Physical Sciences, National University of Trujillo

Period: March 2016 - March 2022

#### Languages

English - Intermediate Spanish - Native

#### Relevant links

Portfolio: https://lmartinez-portfolio.vercel.app/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/lemartinezm/

GitHub: https://github.com/lemartinezm